Guide to the Paul Horgan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Early Acquisitions, 1922-1980; 49.32; (124 Boxes)
  - Writings
    - Manuscripts
      - Reflections on Reaching Thirty, typescript, undated (Box 76)
      - Replies to a Questionnaire..., 1964 (Box 76)
      - Response... Wesleyan, 1967 January 4 (Box 76)
      - The Rio Grande: River of Paradox, carbon typescript, undated (Box 76)
      - Rio Grande: Scenario from Speaker and Orchestra, original typescript, undated (Box 76)
      - Rome Eternal (The Catholic Hour), stenciled typescript, undated (Box 76)
      - Rome Eternal, undated (Box 76)
      - The Saintmaker's Christmas Eve, TV adaptation, notes and typescript, undated; 2 (Box 76)
      - Sanford, Trent. Architecture of the Southwest, review, 1950 (Box 76)
      - A Scandal Narrowly Averted, carbon typescript, undated; 2 (Box 76)
      - The Secret of the Tin Box, carbon typescript, undated (Box 76)
      - Seeds of Humanism in the American Southwest, 1976 July 30 (Box 76)
      - The Sheep, undated; 2 (Box 77)
      - A Small Part of the War Effort, carbon typescript, undated; 2 (Box 77)
      - Songs After Lincoln, original draft, notes, galley sheets, undated (Box 78)
      - Songs After Lincoln, setting copy and galleys, undated (Box 78)
      - A Sort of Gracious Water, xerox of typescript, undated (Box 78)
      - A Speaking Likeness, carbon typescript, 1949 (Box 79)
      - Summer Stock, undated (Box 79)
      - Taos Valley, undated (Box 79)
      - The Telling of the Swan, carbon typescript, undated (Box 79)
      - Terror at Daybreak (formerly The Huntsmen), typescript, undated (Box 79)
      - The Thin Mountain Air, notes, undated; 8 (Box 80)
      - The Thin Mountain Air, notes, undated; 2 (Box 81)
      - The Thin Mountain Air, original second draft, undated (Box 81)
      - The Thin Mountain Air, page proofs, undated (Box 81)
      - Things As They Are, manuscript fragment, undated (Box 81)
      - Things As They Are, notes, undated (Box 81)
      - A Time for Battle, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 81)
      - Toby and the Nighttime, first notes, undated (Box 82)
      - Toby and the Nighttime, typescript, original version, undated (Box 82)
      - A Tree on the Plains, drawings, 1942 (Box 82)
      - A Tree on the Plains, libretto, undated (Box 82)
      - A Tree on the Plains, stencil copy, undated (Box 82)
      - Under the Sun, undated (Box 82)
      - Unexpected Hero (formerly American Adventure), typescript, undated (Box 82)
      - Upstairs, original typescript, undated (Box 82)
      - Wall of Flame, carbon typescript, undated (Box 82)
      - Wall Street Threnody, undated (Box 82)
      - We Never End, undated (Box 82)
      - What You Do With It, unpublished novel, undated (Box 82)
      - Whitewater
        - Working notes, early drafts and proofs, undated (Box 83)
        - Notes not used, undated (Box 83)
        - First complete draft, undated (Box 83)
        - First Complete revised draft, undated (Box 83)
        - Sketch II (discontinued), undated (Box 83)
        - Replacement sheets, xerox of typescript, 1970 (Box 83)
        - Final Draft, undated; 2 (Box 84)
        - Galley proofs, undated (Box 85)
        - Setting Copy, undated; 2 (Box 85)
        - Page proofs, undated (Box 86)
        - Plate proofs, undated (Box 86)
        - Cuts, undated (Box 86)
        - Hamlet parody (deleted), undated (Box 87)
        - Second complete revised draft (xerox), undated (Box 87)
      - Winners and Losers, undated (Box 87)
      - Word and Light, carbon typescript, 1959 (Box 87)
      - Words to Live By, typescript, undated (Box 87)
      - A Writer's Disciplines, carbon typescript, 1962 (Box 87)
      - Wyeth, N.C., Memorial Exhibition catalogue, foreword, 1946 (Box 87)
      - The Young King of Egypt, undated; 2 (Box 88)
      - Yours, A. Lincoln, 1942; 2 (Box 88)
      - Yours, A. Lincoln, script, designs, memorabilia, undated (Box 88)
  - Correspondence
    - Aa-Az, undated (Box 89)
    - Allen, Ed, letter regarding Stravinsky, 1968-1969 (Box 89)
    - Alvarez de Toledo, Alonso, 1964 September 22 (Box 89)
    - American Historians, The Society of, 1963-1966 (Box 89)
    - Amigos de Espana, 1964 (Box 89)
    - Anderson, Clinton P., 1949-1975 (Box 89)
    - Appleby, John, 1971-1973 (Box 89)
    - Artists Equity Association, Inc., 1964 (Box 89)
    - Author's Guild, Inc., 1966 (Box 89)
    - Ba-Bz, 1926-1976 (Box 89)
    - Babin, Victor, 1958-1968 (Box 89)
    - Bacon, Ernest, 1932-1972 (Box 89)
    - Baring, Maurice, letters and materials relating to, 1966-1970 (Box 89)
    - Barzini, Luigi, 1972 (Box 89)
    - Battcock, Gregory, 1965 May 4 (Box 89)
    - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1967-1971 (Box 89)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1971 (Box 89)
    - Berke, Don, 1959-1975; 2 (Box 89)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, 1971 (Box 89)
    - Biggs, John, 1963-1975 (Box 89)
    - Book of the Month Club, 1971-1975 (Box 89)
    - Book of the Month, writing fellowship, 1966 (Box 89)
    - Boettiger, John, 1949 (Box 89)
    - Botkin, B.A., 1926-1931 (Box 89)
    - Bowen, Catherine Drinker, 1970-1972 (Box 89)
    - Brady, Charles, 1965-1973 (Box 90)
    - Broderson, Arvid, 1968 (Box 90)
    - Brown, John, 1965-1970 (Box 90)
    - Butterfield, Victor L., 1965-1975 (Box 90)
    - Buxton, John, 1968-1970 (Box 90)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1926-1965; 3 (Box 90)
    - Letter to Witter Bynner from Paul Engle, December 13 (Box 90)
    - Letter to Witter Bynner from Paul Hollister, 1963 September 8 (Box 90)
    - Letters of Paul Horgan to Witter Bynner, 1926-1963 (Box 90)
    - Ca-Cz, 1926-1972 (Box 90)
    - Campbell, Colin, 1970-1975 (Box 90)
    - Canterbury School, 1965-1966 (Box 90)
    - Capra, Frank, 1966-1971 (Box 90)
    - Cater, Douglass, 1967-1975 (Box 90)
    - Paul Horgan to Douglass Cater, 1964 (Box 90)
    - Catton, Bruce, 1969 March 17 (Box 90)
    - Center Organization, 1966 (Box 90)
    - Chappell, Warren, 1962, 1970 (Box 90)
    - Committee on English Liturgy, 1966 (Box 90)
    - Corcoran, Thomas, 1968-1976 (Box 90)
    - Cornhill Magazine, regarding Maurice Baring material, 1970, 1971 (Box 90)
    - Craft, Robert, 1961-1974 (Box 90)
    - Cromer, Lord, regarding Maurice Baring, November 29 (Box 90)
    - Da-Dz, 1927-1974 (Box 91)
    - Dante Festival, 1965 (Box 91)
    - D'Arcy, Father Martin, 1957-1975 (Box 91)
    - Davidson, Edward, 1967-1969 (Box 91)
    - Davidson, Peter, 1965-1975 (Box 91)
    - Davison Art Center, regarding television, 1962-1964 (Box 91)
    - Dickson, Lovat, 1955-1969 (Box 91)
    - Dobie, J. Frank, 1949-1964 (Box 91)
    - Diocese of Norwich, 1966-1967 (Box 91)
    - Dorrance, 1927 (Box 91)
    - Durand, Marc, 1966-1975 (Box 91)
    - Dubos, Rene, 1965-1972 (Box 91)
    - D'Youville College, 1964-1965 (Box 91)
    - Eastman, 1926-1965 (Box 91)
    - Ea-Ez, 1959-1975 (Box 91)
    - Edel, Leon, 1965-1975 (Box 91)
    - Eliot, T.S., xerox copies, 1960-1964 (Box 91)
    - Eliot, T.S., originals, 1960-1964 (Box 91)
    - Eliot, Valerie, 1975 (Box 91)
    - Etherington, Edwin D., 1966-1971 (Box 91)
    - Fa-Fz, 1927-1972 (Box 92)
    - Fadiman, Clifton, 1970 October 21 (Box 92)
    - Fair, Ronald, 1970-1973 (Box 92)
    - Fergussen, Erna, 1949-1963 (Box 92)
    - Fergussen, Francis, 1964-1976 (Box 92)
    - Letters to Paul Horgan from Francis Fergussen, undated (Box 92)
    - Farrar, Straus, 1960-1975 (Box 92)
    - Flaherty Film Seminar, 1962-1966 (Box 92)
    - Fowles, Jib, 1963-1967 (Box 92)
    - Fremantle, Anne, 1961-1975 (Box 92)
    - Fuller, Robert W., 1967-1973 (Box 92)
    - Ga-Gz, 1967-1975 (Box 92)
    - Gallup, Donald, 1963-1975 (Box 92)
    - Gardner, Paul, 1970-1972 (Box 92)
    - Letter from Paul Horgan to General Gay, 1962 (Box 92)
    - Georgetown, The Dean's Council, 1963; 2 (Box 92)
    - Gill, Brendan, 1971 (Box 92)
    - Girard, Andre, 1961-1964 (Box 92)
    - Giroux, Robert, 1961-1975 (Box 92)
    - Goossens, Eugene and Boonie, 1931, undated (Box 92)
    - Gran, Bishop John, 1964-1970 (Box 92)
    - Green, Samuel M., 1967-1970 (Box 92)
    - Griffin, Martin, 1969-1975 (Box 92)
    - Grant, Jane, 1968 (Box 92)
    - Grant, Rosemary Horgan, 1926-1927 (Box 92)
    - Griswold, Erwin, solicitor general, 1968-1971 (Box 92)
    - Ha-Hz, 1932-1974 (Box 93)
    - Letter from Paul Horgan to Philip Hallie, undated (Box 93)
    - Hancock, Walker, 1970 (Box 93)
    - Hart-Davis, Rupert, 1967 (Box 93)
    - Harvey, Laurence, original plan for film production of A Distant Trumpet, 1961 (Box 93)
    - Hassett, William D., secretary to President Truman, 1948 (Box 93)
    - Henning, Alison and Duke, 1972-1975 (Box 93)
    - Hazzard, Shirley, 1968 (Box 93)
    - Hesburgh, Father Theodore, 1966-1975 (Box 93)
    - Highet, Dr. Gilbert, 1970-1973 (Box 93)
    - Holy Cross, 1963 (Box 93)
    - Letter from Paul Horgan to Edward Horgan, 1963 (Box 93)
    - Letters from Paul Horgan to Robert Hunt, 1932-1955 (Box 93)
    - Letter from Paul Horgan to William Holub regarding Father Murray, undated (Box 93)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1927-1965 (Box 93)
    - Letters to and from family, 1927-1973; 2 (Box 93)
    - Letters by Paul Horgan, 1966-1970 (Box 93)
    - Correspondence concerning Things As They Are, 1964 (Box 93)
    - Letters from Paul Horgan to Virginia Rice, 1961-1974 (Box 93)
    - Houston, George, 1926-1927 (Box 94)
    - Hayes, Helen, undated (Box 94)
    - Telegraph to Helen Hayes regarding One Red Rose for Christmas, undated (Box 94)
    - Houghton Mifflin, 1959-1962 (Box 94)
    - Hughes, Henry, 1971-1973 (Box 94)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1926-1927 (Box 94)
    - Hughes, Stephen, undated (Box 94)
    - Hunt, Robert Nicholas, 1964 (Box 94)
    - Hunter, Dwight, 1971 (Box 94)
    - Hurd, Peter, 1927-1975 (Box 94)
    - Peter Hurd's portrait of President Lyndon Johnson, 1967 (Box 94)
    - Hurd, Mrs. Peter (Henriette Wyeth) and family, 1966-1975 (Box 94)
    - Huxley, Aldous, undated (Box 94)
    - Ia-Iz, 1972-1974 (Box 94)
    - Ja-Jz, 1926-1975 (Box 94)
    - Jeffs, Julian, 1965-1970 (Box 94)
    - Johnson, Lyndon and Lady Bird, 1965-1975 (Box 94)
    - Johnson, Pamela Hansford (Lady Snow), 1961-1975 (Box 94)
    - Johnson, Philip, 1968 (Box 94)
    - Jolliffe, The Honorable John, 1970-1975 (Box 94)
    - Joray, W. Peter, 1967-1972; 2 (Box 94)
    - Letters from Paul Horgan to W. Peter Joray, 1930-1967 (Box 94)
    - Ka-Kz, 1965-1973 (Box 94)
    - Keleher, William A., 1963 (Box 94)
    - Kosinski, Jerzy, undated (Box 94)
    - Kermode, Frank, 1974-1976 (Box 94)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1926-1974 (Box 94)
    - Kraft, James, 1970-1975 (Box 94)
    - Kronenberger, Louis, 1967 (Box 94)
    - La-Lz, 1926-1975 (Box 95)
    - Institute of Contemporary Arts, Linsner Auditorium, George Washington University, Robert Richman, Director, 1964 (Box 95)
    - LaFarge, Oliver, 1949-1969 (Box 95)
    - LaFarge, Mrs. Oliver, undated (Box 95)
    - Materials concerning Archbishop Lamy, 1967-1969; 2 (Box 95)
    - Lea, Tom, 1954-1970 (Box 95)
    - Levy, Miranda, 1961-1972 (Box 95)
    - Lewis, Wilmarth S. (Lefty), 1966-1975 (Box 95)
    - Ma-Mz, 1927-1973 (Box 95)
    - The Library, 1926-1927 (Box 95)
    - Lieberson, Goddard, 1968-1970 (Box 95)
    - Lincoln College, 1965 (Box 95)
    - Lindsay, Vachel, 1922 (Box 95)
    - Longford, Elizabeth, 1970 (Box 95)
    - Longwell, Daniel, 1940 (Box 95)
    - Longworth, Mrs. Alice, 1969-1971 (Box 95)
    - Loyola College, 1964 (Box 95)
    - Lucacz, John, 1970-1973 (Box 95)
    - Luening, Otto, 1927-1966 (Box 95)
    - MacMillan & Co., Ltd. (and Lovat Dickson), 1963 (Box 95)
    - Mamoulian, Reuben, 1926-1975 (Box 95)
    - Manchester, William, 1965-1975 (Box 95)
    - Masland, Robert, 1971-1973 (Box 95)
    - Marcus, Stanley, 1964-1974 (Box 95)
    - Martin, John Bartlow, undated (Box 95)
    - Mayer, Tom, 1975 (Box 95)
    - Meissner, Wallace, 1971-1975 (Box 96)
    - Mencken, H.L., 1921-1937 (Box 96)
    - Meredith, William, 1967-1975 (Box 96)
    - Messer, Thomas, 1967-1975 (Box 96)
    - Letter from Paul Horgan to Thomas Messer, 1964 December 29 (Box 96)
    - Metropolitan Opera, 1964-1965 (Box 96)
    - Milton, General Hugh M., II, 1964-1973 (Box 96)
    - Michie, James, 1964-1974 (Box 96)
    - Moe, Henry Allen, 1961-1975 (Box 96)
    - Letter from Paul Horgan to Henry Allen Moe, 1963-1970 (Box 96)
    - Monroe, Harriet, 1922-1926 (Box 96)
    - Moynihan, D.P. and family, 1966-1975 (Box 96)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1970 (Box 96)
    - Munson, Gorham, 1968-1973 (Box 96)
    - Murray, Gregory, 1970-1971 (Box 96)
    - Murray, John Courtney, S.J., 1966 (Box 96)
    - Na-Nz, 1926-1976 (Box 96)
    - Nabokov, Nicolas, 1971 (Box 96)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, undated; 2 (Box 96)
    - National Book Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 96)
    - National Film Library, 1963 (Box 96)
    - New York Times Book Review, 1966 (Box 97)
    - Nevins, Allan, 1954-1967 (Box 97)
    - Notre Dame- library council, 1964-1976 (Box 97)
    - Oa-Oz, 1926-1975 (Box 97)
    - Pa-Pz, 1926-1975 (Box 97)
    - O'Gorman, Ned, 1966 (Box 97)
    - Pauley, Edwin W., 1963-1964 (Box 97)
    - Pawlowski, Fran, 1970-1973 (Box 97)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1966-1975 (Box 97)
    - Pemberton, Brock, 1949 (Box 97)
    - Phaedra, 1964 (Box 97)
    - The Philosophical Society of Texas, 1965-1966 (Box 97)
    - Polymus and letter from Jon Lee, 1968 (Box 97)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1967-1976 (Box 97)
    - Pulitzer prize, 1964 (Box 97)
    - Ra-Rz, 1929-1973 (Box 97)
    - Read, Sir Herbert, 1964-1968 (Box 97)
    - Reed, Kit and Joseph, 1964-1975; 2 (Box 97)
    - Reeve, Franklin D. and family, 1954-1975; 2 (Box 97)
    - Reeve, F.D., includes The Revolution that Won't Happen, 1972, undated (Box 98)
    - Rice, Virginia, her Horgan files, 1928-1936; 10 (Box 98)
    - Rice, Virginia, her Horgan files, 1937-1948; 11 (Box 99)
    - Rice, Virginia, her Horgan files, 1949-1955; 7 (Box 100)
    - Rice, Virginia, correspondence with and about Paul Horgan, 1955-1962; 8 (Box 101)
    - Rice, Virginia, correspondence with and about Paul Horgan, 1963-1973; 14 (Box 102)
    - Rice, Virginia, will and probate proceedings, 1975 (Box 102)
    - Richards, I.A., 1967-1975 (Box 102)
    - Rinehart & Company, 1954-1965 (Box 102)
    - Ripley, Dillon, 1965 (Box 102)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1964-1966 (Box 103)
    - Sa-Sz, 1926-1976 (Box 103)
    - Rose, Stuart, 1950-1974 (Box 103)
    - Rosenbaum, Robert, 1967-1975 (Box 103)
    - Rosten, Leo, undated (Box 103)
    - Saint Joseph College, board of associate trustees, 1964-1966 (Box 103)
    - St. Michael's College, library committee, 1965 (Box 103)
    - Santa Fe Opera, 1965-1966 (Box 103)
    - Saxton, Eugene and Mark, 1965-1968 (Box 103)
    - School of American Research, 1964-1973; 2 (Box 103)
    - Scott, Winfield Townley, 1963-1969; 2 (Box 103)
    - Shrady, Frederick, 1966 (Box 103)
    - Simmons Ernest, J., 1964-1970 (Box 103)
    - Sitwell, Sir Osbert, 1955 (Box 103)
    - Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1926-1927 (Box 103)
    - Snow, C.P., 1961-1975 (Box 103)
    - Snow, Wilbert, 1966-1972; 2 (Box 103)
    - Spender, Stephen, 1967-1968 (Box 104)
    - Society of Fellows (Harvard University), 1963 (Box 104)
    - Spike, John and Michele, 1973-1975 (Box 104)
    - Stafford, Jean, 1968-1971 (Box 104)
    - Steegmuller, Francis, 1970 (Box 104)
    - Stegner, Wallace, 1968-1975 (Box 104)
    - Straus, Dorothea, 1967-1976 (Box 104)
    - Straus, Roger, 1956-1974 (Box 104)
    - Stravinsky, Igor and Vera, 1960-1971 (Box 104)
    - Sullivan, Frank, 1966-1974; 2 (Box 104)
    - Ta-Tz, 1927-1976 (Box 104)
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1969 (Box 104)
    - Tinkle, Lon, 1966-1971 (Box 104)
    - Trey, W., 1957, 1968, undated (Box 104)
    - Tryon, Thomas, 1971-1975 (Box 104)
    - Ua-Uz, 1961-1965 (Box 104)
    - U.S. Film Archive, 1963-1964 (Box 104)
    - University Club, 1964 (Box 104)
    - Va-Vz, 1926-1973 (Box 104)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1927, undated (Box 104)
    - Vincent, Alan, 1971 (Box 104)
    - Walker, John, 1970 (Box 104)
    - Wa-Wz, 1957-1976 (Box 104)
    - Walsh, Richard, 1971-1973 (Box 104)
    - Walton, Clarence, 1972 (Box 104)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1970, 1975 (Box 104)
    - Weeks, Jack, 1965-1976 (Box 104)
    - Wescott, Glenway, 1969 (Box 104)
    - Wheeler-Booth, M., 1969-1970 (Box 104)
    - White, Robert, 1971 (Box 104)
    - Wilbur, Mr. and Mrs. Richard, 1970-1975 (Box 104)
    - Wilder, Thorton, 1976, undated (Box 104)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1965-1971 (Box 104)
    - Worth, Robert, 1955-1975 (Box 104)
    - Wyeth, Andrew and family, 1931-1975 (Box 104)
    - X-Z, 1926-1975 (Box 105)
    - Zorina, Vera, 1961-1975 (Box 105)
    - Unidentified, 1926-1976 (Box 105)
    - Notes and correspondence, 1956-1975; 4 (Box 105)
    - Notes and drafts, 2 (Box 105)
    - Letters from readers, 1962-1971 (Box 106)
    - The Santa Fe Opera, correspondence and notes (Box 106)
    - Lord and Lady Snow, 1970 (Box 106)
    - Fan mail, 1959-1976 (Box 106)
    - Letters regarding artwork, 1971 (Box 106)
    - A Distant trumpet, correspondence, 1959-1972 (Box 106)
    - Lamy of Santa Fe, correspondence, 1955-1975; 2 (Box 106)
    - Maurice Baring Restored, correspondence (Box 106)
    - Whitewater, Reader's Digest, correspondence (Box 106)
  - Printed material
    - Clippings and momentos, undated; 4 (Box 107)
    - Terra Nostra by Carlos Fuentes, uncorrected proof, 1976; 2 (Box 108)
    - Goodbye, Darkness: A Memoir of the Pacific War by William Manchester, uncorrected proof, 1980 (Box 108)
    - World of Nothing by Ronald L. Fair, two novellas, 1970 (Box 108)
    - The Caseworker by George Konrad, uncorrected proof, 1974 (Box 108)
    - Photographs, postcards, and sketches, undated (Box 109)
    - Pamphlets, programs, brochures, and invitations, 1966-1972; 2 (Box 109)
    - Offprints, reprints, and galleys, 1966-1975 (Box 109)
    - Clippings, 1972 (Box 109)
    - Financial statements and contracts, 1970-1973 (Box 110)
    - Magazines and small publications, 1971-1974 (Box 110)
    - Materials concerning Great River, 1945 (Box 110)
    - Notes and correspondence, 1965-1978 (Box 110)
    - Black Snowflakes, undated (Box 110)
    - Drawings, undated (Box 110)
  - Materials relating to military service
    - Desk diaries of Lt. Col. Paul Horgan, 1945-1946 (Box 111)
    - Correspondence and writings, 1942, undated (Box 111)
    - Secret Trash, notes on Frank Capra, undated (Box 111)
    - The Second Lieutenant's War, undated (Box 111)
    - Zone of the Interior: War Sketches 1941-1943, undated (Box 111)
    - Fast Company, partial script, 1977, undated (Box 111)
    - A Pretty Rugged Time of It, undated (Box 111)
    - From the Battle of Hollywood, undated; 2 (Box 111)
    - Wartime notes, undated (Box 111)
    - Correspondence and notes, undated (Box 111)
    - Membership certificate from The Philosophical Society of Texas, undated (Box 111)
    - Correspondence addressed to Eric Knight relating to World War II service, xerox copies, undated (Box 111)
    - Secret Trash, first draft, undated (Box 111)
    - Notebooks kept by Paul Horgan during 1942 tour of OCS system (Box 111)
    - Wallets S.T.1 and S.T.2 with notes for planned book about Paul Horgan service in Army, 1942-1946 (Box 111)
      - I. The Portents, undated (Box 111)
      - II. Pentagon I, undated (Box 111)
      - III. OCS tour I & II and Hollywood, undated (Box 111)
      - IV. Pentagon II, undated (Box 111)
      - V. The Branch, undated (Box 111)
      - VI. ETO, undated (Box 111)
      - VII. Over and Out, undated (Box 111)
  - Audiovisual material
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Out of the Rubble, undateed; 1; reel to reel tapes, 5" tape (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Paul Horgan interview, 1965; 1; reel to reel tapes, 7" tape (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Top of the Bookshelf, Helen Reed talks about Encounters with Stravinsky, 1973; 1; reel to reel tapes, 7" tape (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Great River, undated; 1; reel to reel tapes, 7" tape (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Pen-Portraits, Dr. Paul Horgan and Robin Preising, undated; 1; reel to reel tapes, 7" tape (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Speech from the Metropolitan Opera, undated; 1; reel to reel tapes, 4" tape (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - German radio recording, undated; 1; reel to reel tapes, 4" tape (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Babin Memorial, undated; 1 (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Interview with Paul Horgan by Heywood Hale Brown, undated; 1 (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Peter Hurd, taped by Keith Kolb, 1979; 1 (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
  - Oversize
    - The Great River, text by Paul Horgan, music by Ernest Bacon (Box 112 (Oversize))
    - Lamy of Santa Fe, printed material, 1975-1976, undated; 5 (Box 113 (Oversize))
    - Artwork
      - Drawings for Great River
        - Accompanying material for exhibitions, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande at Del Rio/ Villa Acuna, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande at Brownsville, Texas, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Point of confluence, Pecos and Rio Grande, near Langtry, Texas, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Elephant Butte Lake, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Old House, Roma, Texas, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande at Cochiti, New Mexico, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Woodburning locomotive, Brownsville, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Big Bend- After a Shower, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Between San Ygnacio, and Laredo, 1969 April 19 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande above San Acacio Dam, New Mexico, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande near Mission/ Madras, Texas, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Woman's dress, 1860, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - International bridge of Eagle Pass, Texas, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Dust Storm, Albuquerque, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Laredo faces- men, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Diagram of Santa Elena Canyon, Big Bend, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Courthouse, Marfa, Texas, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Ruins of Ft. Craig, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Zapata Co. Courthouse, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Mouth of the Rio Grande, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Unidentified drawing, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande at Albuquerque, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - RIo Grande Pyramid, Colorado, 1945 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Dust Storm, Albuquerque, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande at San Antonio, New Mexico, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Cristobal Mountains, New Mexico, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande near McNary, Texas, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Fraz Cristobal Mountain, New Mexico, 1952 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Fraz Cristobal Range, New Mexico, 1952 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Quilt Block Pattern, "Turkey Track", 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Corn shuck broom, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Ruins of Ft. Selden, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Ruins of Ft. Craig, 1949 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Spanish knife, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - San Elizario Mission, 1949 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Valley at Presidio, Texas, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Charles V, after Titian, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Side wheel steamboat, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grand at Langtry, Texas, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Copper Mug, Eagle Pass, 1950 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - River bottom near Espanda, New Mexico, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - RIo Chama above Abiquiu, New Mexico, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))